Varnel Joseph

1 514 549-8140 • E-mail jvarnel@gmail.com • http://linkedin.com/in/varnel-j-62330a1a

PROFIL

Full Stack Web Developer

Strong experience in web applications

In-depth knowledge of web frameworks and technologies

First class analytical, API design and problem solving skills, experience in infrastructure and services modernization, programming knowledge of Ruby on Rails, Javascript, NodeJs, React, experimented with AWS cloud services

Excellent ability with distributed teams, well organized, motivated, aptitude to learn new skills

English and French

.....

WORK EXPERIENCE

Architect, Full Stack Web Developer

2020-2022

Asalys Inc - asalys.com • Remote

- Architected and developed several online solutions challengeprize.com - competitions contest based on multimedias cityfew.com - pre-sales and post-sales programmatic e-commerce platform
- Architected and developed queued solutions for multimedia transcoding, payment, multi-database access and telemetry systems
- Created and developed multi-cloud deployment scripts

Full Stack Web Developer, Team Lead

2017-2020

Native Touch - nativetouch.com • Montreal

- Collaborated with product manager and development teams to define, gather and improverequirements
- Developed interactive customer portal for canada wide advertising campaign insights
- Developed features on the internal ad operators portal to facilitate advertising campaigns
- Improved, consolidated and maintained the CI/CD processes
- Participated to the ad placement, ad attribution through geolocation
- Attended to various presentations and conferences on "cloud" innovations

Software Engineer

2014-2016

CA Technologies - ca.com • Vancouver

- Developed AWS Cloud provision scripts
- Developed an hybrid infrastructure integration to support cloud / on-premise APIs
- Participated to technical committees to improve processes across teams
- Supported quality engineers to setup, develop and enforce automated testing
- Trained in <u>Scaled Agile Framework</u>
- Implemented various features on the portal cloud user interface
- Improved and maintained integration tests of the portal cloud
- Integrated with GoodData to display client APIs reporting

Web Developer 2012-2013

TheLevel Consulting - thelevel.com • Vancouver

- Developed a social networking platform for Rogers marketing team
- Implemented new user interface features for Layer7 API Management Portal
- Tested and fixed user interface securities of Layer7 API Management Portal
- Integrated and maintained widgets on <u>Hawai Official Tourism Website</u>
- Developed tools to facilitate internal development processes
- Configured a ready to launch Drupal CMS
- Modernized features on the company CMS
- Improved the interface to manage translation review process

Software Engineer

2012-2012

GUST - Angelsoft Inc - gust.com • Vancouver

- · Worked as lead to migrate the user interface from Java to Ruby on Rails
- Developed various new user interfaces features
- Mentored one developer to write and maintain test codes
- Awarded SIIA CODIE 2012 Best Collaboration / Social Networking Solution

Consultant 2011-2012

GUST - Angelsoft Inc - gust.com • Vancouver

- Configured and updated automated tests
- Mentored one developer to write and maintain test codes
- Integrated and fixed small user interface features

Web Developer 2010-2011

Onmaas Inc • Vancouver

- Developed cross-platform APIs integration, Facebook, Linkedin, Twitter, Emails, etc.
- Implemented the automated test architecture
- Implemented and wrote performance tests
- Documented new code on the company wiki

Consultant, Full Stack Developper

2010- ...

Omnis Moves Inc • Vancouver

- Developed various dashboards to manage moves activity
- Created HTML5 for movers to have clients record, sign, and pay for their moves
- Automated payrolls and financials reports
- Integrated with various payment platforms
- Architected an affiliate system
- Designed, evaluated and maintained service performance on AWS Cloud

EDUCATION

Google Project Management Certificate

2022

Coursera, Online

Licence de Science et Technologie - Mention Informatique Université Pierre & Marie Curie, Paris

2008

Dropout ~ 110/180